

PARVATHY VAZHOOR WEB DEVELOPER

- parvathyvd@gmail.com
 - **3** 604-358-3962
- in linkedin.com/in/parvathy-vazhoor
 - odepen.io/parvathyvd
 - github.com/parvathyvd

PORTFOLIO

https://webfolio.realwordpressdevelopment.com/

EDUCATION

Bachelors Degree in Computer Science

Vidya Academy of Science & Technology, India

LANGUAGES

English

Hindi

OTHER INTERESTS

Biking

Glass Painting

Dancing

CONTACT ADDRESS

8277 161st Surrey BC, V4N0N3

CAREER PROFILE

I am a web developer specializing in Front end development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, PHP(Codeigniter) and Vanila Javascript(Jquery,React). Strong background in Wordpress web development and design.

WORK HISTORY

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER (FREELANCER)

REALWORDPRESSDEVELOPMENT (09/2020 to Present)

Developed web apps using HTML5, CSS3, BOOTSTRAP and Javascript(React).

Developed custom websites using Wordpress CMS.

Developed custom themes, Set up the stripe payment checkout using glass register for charity websites for Frontier (contract work).

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

RSTINSTRUMENTS (09/2018 Sep to 09/2020)

Responsible for redeveloping the RST website.

Upgraded the HTML website to custom **PHP** website and **MYSQL** database with newer design. Designed and developed website using PHP, HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript ES6.

Migrated and redeveloped the entire website with same design in to the **Wordpress**.

WEB DEVELOPER/DESIGNER

BRIKERS (05/2017 to 07/2018)

Developed Brikers website wireframe using Lucidchart.

Developed brikers website using Codeigniter(PHP framework), Bootstrap and jquery. Used SASS preprocessor.

Tested webpage for responsiveness and adjusted the media queries accordingly.

WEB DEVELOPER/DESIGNER

ENGAGEMEDIA (07/2013 to 04/2017)

Responsible for all stages of Web site creations for client, from initial design and architecture to development, deployment, and management.

Developed websites mainly **Wordpress CMS**. Responsible for Domain registration, Webhosting, Wordpress, theme, plugin installation and customization.

Developed custom wordpress templates

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3 (SASS,SCSS) Bootstrap Javascript ES6 & Jquery WordPress PHP7, Codeigniter React Npm, Webpack & Babel **MYSQL** Lucidchart, Asana Photoshop, Illustrator, Figma Git & Github & Terminal Email Marketing & SEO Google Search Console Google Tag Manager Godaddy & Hostgator Mailchimp Filezila VSC, Phpstorm, Atom, Coda2, Dreamweaver **MAMP**

